A Guide to the Alice Langley Hsieh Papers, 1943-1978
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Alice Langley Hsieh Papers, 1943-1978
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1979-004
8.0 cu. ft. 8 boxes
The Alice Langley Hsieh collection consists of three parts: (1) the personal papers and publications of Alice Langley Hsieh (1922-1979), a U.S. State Department, RAND corporation, and Institute for the Defense Analyses specialist on the military of the People's Republic of China; (2) the manuscripts of books written by her spouse, C. Kien Hsieh, himself an authority on Communist China; and (3) collateral publications from A. L. Hsieh's library on the Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA), the Maoist Cultural Revolution, Chinese nuclear capability, Japanese security fources, and other Far Eastern topics and issues.
Hsieh, Alice Langley, 1922-1979
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Alice Langley Hsieh Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1979.
Biographical Note
Born Alice Edith Langley, Hsieh graduated from Queens College (Flushing, New York) in 1943 and did graduate work at Clark University (history and international relations), Stanford University (history and U.S. Foreign Policy), George Washington University (law), and the University of California at Berkeley (Chinese). She became an International Relations Officer and Foreign Service Officer for the Bureau of Far Eastern Affairs of the U.S. State Department (1945-1955) and was a member of the U.S. Delegation to the Far Eastern Commission (1946-1952). In 1951, she served as Special Assistant to the U.S. Political Advisor to the Supreme Commander of the Allied Powers, Tokyo, Japan.
From 1955 to 1958, Hsieh served as a consultant to the RAND Corporation and became a member of the RAND Senior Staff (1958-1969), specializing in Communist China's foreign policy, military doctrine and developments (including nuclear), internal Army-Party relations, Sino-Japanese relations, and general security matters in the Far East.
In 1969, she joined the International and Social Studies Division of the Institute for Defense Analyses (IDA) as a research staff member, continuing to specialize in the same areas. From 1971 to 1973, she was incapacitated be a serious illness, regaining a limited level of activity in the latter year. She continued to write, do research, and accumulate reference materials through 1978, but her active publication period is confined to the earlier years. Hsieh served as a consultant to the U.S. State Department throughout her later career, and appeared several times before Congressional committees, testifying on Communist China's nuclear capability and intentions, and on the development of a U.S. Anti-China anti-ballistic missile system.
Hsieh died in November 1979.
Scope and Content
The Alice Langley Hsieh collection consists of three parts: (1) the personal papers and publications of Alice Langley Hsieh (1922-1979), a U.S. State Department, RAND corporation, and Institute for the Defense Analyses specialist on the military of the People's Republic of China; (2) the manuscripts of books written by her spouse, C. Kien Hsieh, himself an authority on Communist China; and (3) collateral publications from A. L. Hsieh's library on the Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA), the Maoist Cultural Revolution, Chinese nuclear capability, Japanese security fources, and other Far Eastern topics and issues.
Arrangement
The Hsieh collection consists of 9 boxes. The collection contains three series: Series I: Alice Langley Hsieh Papers; Series II: C. Kien Hsieh Papers; and Series III: Subject Files.
Series I: Alice Langley Hsieh Papers contains biographical information, correspondence, manuscript materials, publications, work files, and presentation notes. This series is arranged by material type. Within each material type, items are arranged chronologically, whenever possible.
Series II: C. Kien Hsieh Papers contains manuscript chapters from publications, as well as research notes. This series is in its orignal order.
Series III: Subject Files contains reference materials collected by Hsieh throughout her career. Topics generally related to China and other parts of Asia. Please note: Many items or files in this series are cross-referenced with previous series. Notes regarding cross-references are included in the item/file description. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject file title. Within each subject file, items are arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Series I: Alice Langley Hsieh Papers, 1943-1978.
  - Biographical sketches and vitae of Alice Langley Hsieh. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1974. (Box 1)
    - From C. J. Hinton, Abe Halpern, and others re: strategy and tactics of Communist China's foreign policy toward Japan, 10/56-10/74.
    - From Allen S. Whiting; commendation on paper regarding the Soviet-Sino Nuclear Dialogue, 3/26/64.
    - From Brownlee Hayden, with materials on Edgar Snow, including his interview with Mao Tse Tung, Spring 1965.
    - From R. Liang, with a review of Chen Yu-chen, "The New Stage of the Cultural Revolution," 3/20/67.
    - From Ellis Joffe, with prepublication cope of "The PLA in Politics and Politics in the PLA," c.1967.
    - From Lew Crampton, with ms pp 46-89 and bibliography for paper on Mao's perception of the miltiary role in the Cultural Revolution, 2/8/68.
    - From Heather Hinton, regarding a paper on the PLA and Sino-Soviet relations, 4/8/68.
    - From Lew Crampton, with rough draft of a paper on "where the Cultural Revolutino is heading," 9/2/68.
    - From Parris Chang, with a copy of article in Problems of Communism "China in Flux: A Second Decade of Maoist Rule," 11/12/69.
    - A general correspondence file, incoming and outgoing, on a variety of subjects, 1968-1969.
    - A file of miscellaneous correspondence, 8/69 to 12/69.
    - A file of correspondence, including letters from Sen. Albert Gore, and Mr. John McCloy, commending ALH testimony and analyses, 1/70-6/70.
    - To a broad distribution list, the memo of her converstaions with Kiichi Saeki re: Japanese security issues.
    - A file of correspondence, including letter informing her of her election to the Institute for Strategic Studies, London, 7/70-12/70.
    - To William Stewart, RAND Corp., with her review of RAND Doc R-548-PR "The Purge of Lo Jui-ch'ing: The Politics of Chinese Strategic Planning," 9/17/70.
    - A file of incoming correspondence, most re book reviews, invitations to speak, paper calls, society memeberships, etc., 11/70-7/75.
    - Memo re letter from Makoto Momoi re: Japanese defense budget, 1/6/71.
    - From Parris Chang, with his paper "The Role of Ch'en Po-Ta in the Cultural Revolution," c.1971.
    - Request from Connie Wall, Stockholm International Peace Research Institute for review of draft section re China's Policies on Armament, writtein for 1971 Yearbook on Armament and Disarmament, 1/17/72.
    - From Harry E. T. Thayer with his paper "The China Factor in the ABM Debate: Chronicle of a Rationale," 5/26/71
    - From Ellis Joffe, with his paper, "The Chinese Army After the Cultural Revolution: The Effects of Intervention," c.9/73.
    - From Edward T. Fei, re attitude scaling exercise to assess Chinese attitude change toward West, 4/8/74.
  - Personal Files, 1965-1978, n.d.
    - Card file of references to Chinese officials, alphabetical by name; manuscript notes on PLA and Chinese military. (Box 9)
    - File of manuscript notes on various topics, as originiall filed. Organization indeterminate. (Box 9)
    - Files coded "C15," by month, 2/65-12/65. (Box 1)
    - Folders also coded "C15," translations of foreign broadcasts, most re PLA), November and December 1965. (Box 1)
    - File on the U.S.-North Korea relations, including Pueblo incident, 1968-1969. (Box 1)
    - Files "E5a," re N. Korea, U.S.-DPRK relations, and USSR-DPRK relations, 1968-1969. (Box 1)
    - File "E5b," re South Korea, 1969. (Box 1)
    - Files "E6" through "E9," re USSR, 1969. (Box 1)
    - File "E8," re Soviet role in Asia, 1969. (Box 1)
    - File "F1," re ABM in NIxon adminstration, and Sino-Soviet border relations, 1969. (Box 1)
    - File "H1," background on Nixon administration's Vietnam and China policies, 1969. (Box 1)
    - File "H3," on test ban and non-proliferation treaties, 1969. (Box 1)
    - File "H4," on Asian military ties and nuclear arms standoff, 1969. (Box 2)
    - File "H5," on nuclear arms control, 1969. (Box 2)
    - File "H6," on thaw in U.S.-China relations (includes H. Scoop Jackson speech), 1969. (Box 2)
    - File "H7," on U.S.-Japan relations, 1969. (Box 2)
    - File title "J. Research on Taiwan," re criticism of ruling Kuomintang, 1969. (Box 2)
    - File titled "Memorandums" including memo to Paul Nitze re ALH's conversations with Soviet officials on arms control, 3/24/70. (Box 2)
    - File of original newsclippings on various China and arms topics, most from Washington Post, some New York Times, 1975-1978. (Box 2)
  - Manuscripts, c.1943-1971, n.d. (Box 2)
    - "Economic Totalitarianism in Japan," [Undergraduate course paper?], c.1943.
    - Typed ms "The Red River (U.S.-Canada) Settlement: Its Argicultural Development," [Undergraduate paper?], n.d.
    - "The Strategy and Tactics of Communist China's Foreign Policy Toward Japan," 9/4/56.
    - Draft of "Communist China's Attitude on Disarmament and Arms Control," 3/64.
    - Working papers for "The Role of the PLA in China's Cultural Revolution," 12/67.
    - Draft and notes for "The Role of the PLA in China's Cultural Revolution," c.1968.
    - Drafts of [book?] sections on the role of the military in the "Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution," 1/4/67-5/21/68.
    - Untitled ms on Japan's attitudes and decisions regarding the Chinese nuclear threat, [some pages stamped "Secret], c.10/68.
    - Typed paper, "The Cultural Revolution, Spring 1968," c.1968.
    - "Some Implications for Japan of Communist China's Space/Missile Developments," c.1968.
    - Pre-issue copy of a study on Japan's Defense Policies, c.1969.
    - "China's Nuclear Strategy and a U.S. Anti-China ABM," 7/9/70.
    - "The Role of Active Defense in CC's Military Strategy and Doctrine," c.1970.
    - Draft of "CC's Military Policy in the 1970s: The Impact of Current Doctrine and Policy," mid-1970s.
    - "Primary Projection of Japan's Security Policy," c.1970.
    - Typed and annotated sections of a paper on Japanese defense policy and objectives, 12/70-1/71.
    - Draft of "Current Japanese Defense Plans and Goals," 1/7/71.
    - Typed copy of "The China-Russia Treaty of 1945, Compared," n.d.
  - Master's Thesis, 1944. (Box 2)
    - "American Public Opinion Toward the Sino-Japanese War," 4/25/44.
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1963-1971, n.d. (Box 3)
    - Translation of Kaoru Nakamuru paper on the role of the Red Army in the Cultural Revolution, 12/63.
    - Lecture notes for a course taught at My. Holyoke College, 1965-1966.
    - Typed notes on miscellaneous China topics: Issues in Party, Lin and Chou speeches, Hanoi-Peking Dispute on Strategy, Esoteric Communications, Purges, 1965-1966.
    - Notes for Brussels conferences (Working session on the role of the PLA), 6/17-18/69.
    - Memos of conversations with Boris Davydov, 2nd Secretary of the Soviet Embassy, 9/69-12/69.
    - Notes of interview with Yasamuru Nakasone (then Japan Defense Minister), 1/20/70.
    - Memos of converstaions with Makoto Momoi and Kiichi Saeki re forthcoming visit of Nakasone to U.S., 8/21/70, 2/28/70.
    - Papers forwarded from office of Sen. Henry "Scoop" Jackson re thaw in U.S.-China relations, 1968-1971.
    - Notes re a projected paper on Japan's defense planning, 1/71.
    - Report to unnamed Advisory Group on study of Japan's security forces, 1/27/71.
    - Parallel translations of phonetic Chinese and English of unidentified literary text, n.d.
    - Miscellaneous handwritten notes re Mao, Lin, etc., n.d.
    - Note on George Sarton, "The Reviewing of Learned Books," in 2nd Preface to v.41 of Isis, n.d.
  - Presentations, 1965-1969. (Box 3)
    - Notes and drafts for 9/65 lecture to Air War College, "CC's Military Doctrine and Strategy," and "Elements of Power Affecting Chicom Military Capabilities."
    - CBS News telecast of Sunday 3/16/66, transcript and photo of panel (Hsieh, Marvin Kalb, Sen. Fulbright, et al).
    - Lecture at National Defense College, Tokyo, "CC's Military Policy and Doctrine," 9/17/68.
    - "Some Japanese Attitudes toward Asain Security Issues," 5/2/69.
  - Publications, 1960-1967. (Box 3)
    - Before Subcommittee on Military Applications of the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy, re China's Nuclear Policies, 11/6-11/7/67.
    - Before same committee studtying the ABM, 1/27/70.
    - "Communist China and Nuclear Warfare," 6/60.
    - "The Chinese Genie: Peking's Role in Nuclear Test Ban Negotiations," 6/20/60.
    - "Communist China and Nuclear Warfare," including drafts, in Survival, v. 2, no. 4, 7-8/60.
    - "China, Russia, and the Bomb," in New Leader, 10/17/60.
    - "Red China and Nuclear War," in Military Review, 2/61.
    - "China As an Atomic Power," in Current, 7/62; excerpt from Revue de Defense Nationale, 1/62.
    - A review of "Communist China's Strategy in the Nuclear Era," in Current, 7/62.
    - "Communist China and Nuclear Force," 3/63, and revised 8/63.
    - "Communist China's Military Strategy and Doctrine," 10/63.
    - "The Position of Communist China," in Disarmament, no. 2, 1964.
    - "China's Secret Military Papers," in China Quarterly, 4-6/64.
    - "The Sino-Soviet Nuclear Dialogue, 1963," 6/64, and as reprinted in the Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1/65.
    - Forward to the Japanese edition of Communist China's Strategy in the Nuclear Era, 6/65.
    - Study kit for the AAUW, "The Role of the Military in CC's External Policies," 7/66.
    - RAND Document, "The Upheaval in China and Implications for the Future," 11/18/66.
    - "Presentation on the 'Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution' in China by Roderick McFarquhar, 2/10/67," 3/21/67.
    - Review, A. L. George The CC Army in Action, and S. B. Griffith II, The Chinese PLA, 8/67.
    - Review of J. Gittings, The Role of the Chinese Army, 11/67.
  - Publications, 1968-1971. (Box 4)
    - RAND Document, "Military Confrontation in Asia: The Chinese Viewpoint," 8/23/68.
    - "China's Nuclear Strategy and a U.S. Anti-China ABM," 4/9/70.
    - IDA Paper P-646, "CC's Evolving Military Strategy and Doctrine," with drafts, 6/70.
    - "China's Nuclear Missile Program: Regional or Intercontinental?," in China Quarterly, with drafts, 1-3/71.
- Series II: C. Kien Hsieh Papers, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Manuscript chapters of book Chinese Communism in Action, apparently unpublished, n.d.
  - Manuscript chapter VIII of Communism in China, apparently unpublished, n.d.
  - Manuscript chapters I, IV, and V of Mao and the Chinese Red Army, apparently unpublished, n.d.
  - Manuscript chapters V, VII-1, and VII-2 of untitled book on the PLA, apparently unpublished, n.d.
  - Translation of an article in Kung T'ung Hsien (KTTH), n.d.
  - Notes, in Chinese and English on the critique of an unnamed publication, n.d.
- Series III: Subject Files, 1950-1978.
  - Anti-Ballistic Missiles.
    - "Anti Missile System Shows Soviet-U.S. Collustion," from LeMonde, 9/22/67. (Box 5)
    - A. L. Hsieh testimony before Jackson Subcommittee on Military Uses of Atomic Energy (Filed with ALH Presentations), 11/6-7/67. (Box 3)
    - A. L. Hsieh, "China's Nuclear Strategy and a U.S.-China ABM" (Filed with LSH Mansucripts). (Box 2)
    - Thayer, H. E. T., "The China Factor in the ABM Debate: Chronicle of a Rationale," (Filed with ALH Correspondence), 3/71. (Box 1)
  - Asian Affairs, General.
    - Report of the Conference of Institute for Strategic Studies on the security of Southeast Asia, 8/16-18/63. (Box 5)
    - Adelphi Paper No. 44, "Asian Balance of Power," Coral Bell, 2/68. (Box 5)
    - Chapters 4 and 13, India, China, and Australia, J.D.B. Mileer, editor, 1968. (Box 5)
    - Katheryn E. Young, "The Guam Doctrine: Elements of Implementation--Key State Relations: Australia and Indonesia," 3/70. (Box 5)
  - China, Arms Policy.
    - "China's Policiies on Armament," section from SIPRI 1971 Yearbook (Filed with ALH Correspondence). (Box 1)
  - China, Civil Aviation in.
    - Update of RAND memo RM-4666-PR, "Civil Aviation in Communist China since 1949," (Filed with RAND Documents), 6/66. (Box 7)
    - Typed, author unknown, ms re weather and effects of airport construction and aviation operations. (Box 5)
  - China, Communist Party. (Box 5)
    - Proceedings of National Conference of the Communist Party of China, Foreign Language Press, Peking, March 1955.
    - A file of reports of CCP, 1960-1967.
    - Communique of the 10th Plenary Session of the 8th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, Peking Review, 9/28/62.
    - "Dislocation of Communist Army Political Bureau Activities and the Purge of Hsiao Hua," 3/31/68.
    - "New Internal Power Struggle," Studies in Chinese Communism, 3/31/68.
    - G. Bennett report of interview with informant "Li" re internal problems, 11/27/68.
  - China, Economy.
    - RAND Memo RM-3519-PR, Vols. 1 and 2, "Economy of China's Mainland: National Income and Economic Development, 1953-1959," (Filed with RAND Documents), 4/63. (Box 7)
    - Kang Chou, "Indicies of Industrial Output in Communist China," 8/63. (Box 5)
  - China, General.
    - File of miscellaneous reporints on aggression, co-existance, arms control, etc., 1964-1966. (Box 5)
    - Vice Premier Chen Yi's remarks at a foreign press conference, 9/29/65. (Box 5)
    - RAND Paper, "Upheaval in China and Implications for the Future," (Filed with RAND Documents), 11/8/66. (Box 7)
    - Alexandra Close, "Revolutionary Fission," in Far Eastern Review, 1/19/67. (Box 5)
    - Parris Chang, "China in Flux: A Second Decade of Maoist Rule," (Filed with ALH Correspondence). (Box 1)
    - C. K. Hsieh, Chinese Communism in Action, (Filed with CKH Papers). (Box 4)
    - C. K. Hsieh, Communism in China, (Filed with CKH Papers). (Box 4)
  - China Mainland Press Service Reports. (Box 5)
    - File of reports from 8/65, 9/65, and 11/65.
  - China, Maps. (Box 5)
    - Anti Japanese Democratic Bases in 1945, 8/65.
  - China, Military.
    - Ho Yu Wen, "The Chicom Military Organization," in Freedom Front, 7/20/59. (Box 5)
    - File of miscellaneous PLA-related documents, 1960-1966. (Box 5)
    - Anne Clark, Biographies of Military Leaders, 7/64. (Box 5)
    - Republic of China Intelligence Arm, Chinese Military Leaders, 7/64. (Box 5)
    - W. W. Whitson, Military Campaigns in China, 1924-1950, 9/66. (Box 5)
    - Ellis Joffe, "The PLA in Politics," 11/30/66. (Box 5)
    - A review of The Politics of the Chinese Red Army, 1966. (Box 5)
    - PLA Unit History, hardbound and xerox copies, c.1966-1967. (Box 5)
    - PLA Unit Reference Book, hardbound and xerox copies, c.1966-1967. (Box 5)
    - L. Crampton, "The PLA in Politics and Politics in the PLA," 9/67. (Box 5)
    - ALH Lecture on CC's Military Doctrines and Policy, (Filed with ALH Presentations), 9/65. (Box 3)
    - ALH Lectures "Elements of Power Affecting Chicom Military Capabilities," (Filed with ALH Presentations), 9/65. (Box 3)
    - Chronology, "Interpretation of Military Events," 1965. (Box 5)
    - "The Army's Role in the Cultural Revolution," in China Report, v. 4. no. 2, 3-4/68. (Box 5)
    - W. W. Whitson, "The CC High Command: Roles and Perceptions in 1969," also draft of the same, 3/18/69. (Box 5)
    - Yuan-Li Wu, ed., China: A Handbook, ch. 10 "The People's Liberation Army," Ellis Joffe, c.1972 (Box 5)
    - Ms book chapters, C. K. Hsieh, on the PLA. (Box 4)
    - Ms chapters, C. K. Hsieh, Mao and the Chinese Red Army. (Box 4)
    - Ellis Joffe, "The PLA in Politics and Politics in the PLA," ms (Filed with ALH Correspondence). (Box 1)
    - Yen Chien-ying and PLA Training, a RAND Document. (Box 7)
    - Chinese language military training manuals, (Filed with Chinese Language, Documents in). (Box 7)
  - China News Analysis. (Box 5)
    - Issues no. 631 (re sayings of Mao) and 634/671 (re youth corps), 4-8/64.
    - Articles on a variety of topics, from Issues between 11/4/66 and 11/10/67.
  - China, Nuclear Armament and Research. (Box 5)
    - File of reprints, 1961-1965
    - J. D. Pollack, "Chinese Attitudes Toward Nuclear Weapons, 1964-69," Chi Wang, "Nuclear Research in Communist China," c.1965.
  - China, Policy-Making in. (Box 5)
    - M. Oksenberg, "Policy Formation Processes in the CPR, 1949-1968," East Asian Institute, Columbia U., 8/69.
    - Bibliography and selected papers on public decision-making, especially in Communisy China, 1969
    - T. Weiss, "The Role of the PLA in Foreign Policy Formation," 1/70.
  - China Reporting Service reprints. (Box 6)
    - Selections of reprints filed chronologically, 1969-1970.
  - Chinese (Mandarin) Langauge.
    - Rulan Chiao Pian, a syllabus for A Mandarin Primer. (Box 6)
    - Glossary of Chinese military terms and translation aids (Pin Yin System), c.1965. (Box 6)
    - An exercise in translation by ALH (Filed with ALH Papers). (Box 3)
  - Chinese Language, Documents in.
    - Letter from General Yeh Hsian-chi, Taiwan (with ALH Correspondence). (Box 1)
    - Issues of KTTH, complete, 11/1/61-8/26-61. (Box 6)
    - Two military training manuals. (Box 6)
    - Copy of Jeifang Jun Bao, Chinese newspaper. (Box 6)
    - Single page photocopy, unidentified. (Box 6)
  - Chou En Lai. (Box 7)
    - RAND Doc D-12245-PR, R. Scalapino, "Chao En Lai in Africa: A Talk with Questions and Answers," (Filed with RAND Documents), 3/64.
    - RAND Document, T. W. Robinson, "Chou En Lai's Role in China's Cultural Revolution," (Filed with RAND Documents), 3/31/69.
  - Crampton, Lew.
    - L. Crampton, "The PLA in Politics and Politics in the PLA," (Filed with China, Military). (Box 5)
    - Typed notes of Crampton regarding the Cultural Revolution, (Filed with China, Military), 1/6-2/67. (Box 6)
    - Two papers, "The Cultural Revolution," (Filed with Cultural Revolution), and "Mao and the Military," (Filed with Mao Tse Tung). (Box 6)
  - Cultural Revolution.
    - File of miscellaneous reprints, 1963-1967. (Box 6)
    - H. Gelman, "Mao and the Permanent Purge," in Problems of Communism,11-12/66. (Box 6)
    - Foreign Language Press pamphlet, "The Great Socialist Cultural Revolution in China," 1966. (Box 6)
    - A. L. Hsieh, working papers for "The Role of the PLA in the CR," (Filed with ALH Papers), c.1966. (Box 3)
    - "Counter-Revolutionary Revisionist Lo Jui-ch'ing is Loaded with Crimes," from Peking Combat News, 1/30/67. (Box 6)
    - Notes of Lew Crampton (Filed with China, Military). (Box 6)
    - Review by R. Liang of "The New Stage of the Cultural Revolution," by Chen Yu-chen, (Filed with ALH Correspondence), 3/20/67. (Box 1)
    - Drafts and notes of ALH for publication, "The Role of the PLA in the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution," (Filed with ALH Papers), c.1967. (Box 2)
    - H. C. Hinton "Policy Making and the Power Struggle in CC During the Cultural Revolution," (Filed with ALH Correspondence), 2/68. (Box 1)
    - ALH Paper "The Cultural Revolution," (Filed with ALH Papers), Spring 1968. (Box 2)
    - "Background and Development of the Proletarian Cultural Revolution," Gene Hsiao, U. of Calif. CCS Report #242, 6/67. (Box 6)
    - Two File of miscellaneous reports, reprints, etc., 1967-1969. (Box 6)
    - "The Army's Role in the Cultural Revolution," in China Report, v. 4, no. 2, 3-4/68. (Box 6)
    - "The Removal of Yang Chen-wu" in Peking Informer, v. 16, no. 8, 4/16/68. (Box 6)